[{"question": "A filter is said to be linear phase filter if the phase delay and group delay are ?", "options": ["A. High", "B. Moderate", "C. Low", "D. Constant"], "answer": "D. Constant"}, {"question": "For which of the following systems, the zeros of the equation of The Transfer Function of  FIR system are outside the unit circle ?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "B. Maximum Phase System"}, {"question": "State the type of system from the transfer function equation of a stable FIR Filter  given as  H(z) =  (( 1-1/2 z)(z-1/4)) / (z-1/3)(z-1/5) ", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "D. Mixed Phase System"}, {"question": "By determining the zeros of the FIR System indicate the type of system for H(z) = 6 + z^-1 - z^-2?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "A. Minimum Phase System"}, {"question": "Classify the type of system by the impulse response of the FIR filter given as h(n) = {1, -5 ,6 } by finding the zeros of the equation?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "B. Maximum Phase System"}, {"question": "For which of the following system, the zeros are on both the left- and right-hand sides of the complex plane and is stable and causal?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "D. Mixed Phase System"}, {"question": "Classify the type of system by the impulse response of the FIR filter given as h(n) = {1, 1.1414,1} by finding the poles of the equation.", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "A. Minimum Phase System"}, {"question": "State the type of system for FIR filter equation H(z) = ((z-1/8)(z-1/6)) / ((z-1/5)(z-1/7)) ?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "A. Minimum Phase System"}, {"question": "Which of the following condition should the unit sample response of a FIR filter satisfy to have a linear phase?", "options": ["A. h(M-1-n) n=0,1,2...M-1", "B. \u00c2\u00b1h(M-1-n) n=0,1,2...M-1", "C. -h(M-1-n) n=0,1,2...M-1", "D. None of the mentioned"], "answer": "B. \u00c2\u00b1h(M-1-n) n=0,1,2...M-1"}, {"question": "Suppose that H(z) and G(z) are rational and have minimum phases. Which of the following filters will have minimum phase?", "options": ["A. H(z) * G(z)", "B. H(z) + G(z)", "C. H(z) - G(z)", "D. H(z) / G(z)"], "answer": "A. H(z) * G(z)"}, {"question": "The roots of the equation H(z) must occur in ?", "options": ["A.Identical", "B. Zero", "C. Reciprocal pairs", "D. Conjugate pairs"], "answer": "C. Reciprocal pairs"}, {"question": "If x(n)=Ae^(jwn) is the input of an LTI system and h(n) is the response of the system, then what is the output y(n) of the system?", "options": ["A.H(-w)x(n)", "B. -H(w)x(n)", "C. H(w)x(n)", "D. None of the mentioned"], "answer": "B. -H(w)x(n)"}, {"question": "A causal system produces the output sequence y(n)={1,0.7} when excited by the input sequence x(n)={1,-0.7,0.1}, then what is the impulse response of the system function?", "options": ["A. [3(0.5)n+4(0.2)n]u(n)", "B. [4(0.5)n-3(0.2)n]u(n)", "C  [4(0.5)n+3(0.2)n]u(n)", "D. None of the mentioned"], "answer": "B. [4(0.5)n-3(0.2)n]u(n)"}, {"question": "Consider two rational  mixed phase systems G(z) and H(z), then which of the following filters will have a mixed phase system?", "options": ["A. H(z) + G(z)", "B. H(z) * G(z)", "C. (H(z))/(G(z))", "D. All of the above"], "answer": "D. All of the above"}, {"question": "If H(z) is the z-transform of the impulse response of an FIR filter, then create a relation from the following which is true?", "options": ["A. z^(M+1).H(z^(-1)) = \u00c2\u00b1H(z)", "B. z^(-(M+1)).H(z^(-1)) =\u00c2\u00b1H(z)", "C.z^(M-1).H(z^(-1)) =\u00c2\u00b1H(z)", "D. z^(-(M-1)).H(z^(-1)) =\u00c2\u00b1H(z)"], "answer": "D. z^(-(M-1)).H(z^(-1)) = \u00c2\u00b1H(z)"}, {"question": " A minimum phase unity feedback system has a bode plot with a constant slope of -20dB/decade for all frequencies. What is the value of the maximum phase margins of the system?", "options": ["A. 0\u00c2\u00b0", "B. 90\u00c2\u00b0", "C. -90\u00c2\u00b0", "D. 180\u00c2\u00b0"], "answer": "B. 90\u00c2\u00b0 "}, {"question": "For minimum phase systems:", "options": ["A. Pole must lie on left plane", "B. Zeroes must lie on left plane", "C. Poles and zeroes must lie on left plane", "D. Both must lie on right plane"], "answer": "C. Poles and zeroes must lie on left plane "}, {"question": "For non-minimum phase systems:", "options": ["A.Poles and zeroes must lie on the right s-plane", "B. Zeroes must lie on right of s-plane", "C. Both lie on left of s-plane", "D. Poles must be on the left and zeroes can be on the right s \u00e2\u20ac\u201cplane."], "answer": "D. Poles must be on the left and zeroes can be on the right s \u00e2\u20ac\u201cplane."}, {"question": "If the frequency response of an FIR system is given as H(z)= 1 - 2.5z^-1 - 1.5z^-2, then the system is?", "options": ["A. Minimum Phase System", "B. Maximum Phase System", "C. Linear Phase System", "D. Mixed Phase System"], "answer": "D. Mixed Phase System"}, {"question": "The poles of a digital filter with linear phase response can lie?", "options": ["A. Only at z = 0", "B. Only on the unit circle", "C. Only inside the unit circle but not at z = 0", "D. On the left side of Real (z) = 0 line"], "answer": "B. Only on the unit circle"}, {"question": "FFT is used to calculate", "options": ["A DFT", "B Z Transform", "C DTFT", "D Inverse DTFT"], "answer": "A"}]